faithlife.com 2019-05-15

# Privacy Policy - Faithlife

### Visiting

We record standard information on site visitors, including IP addresses, times and dates, referring/exit pages, operating systems, clickstreams, web browser brands and versions, pages visited, demographic data, and user-interface languages. Our sites set cookies in order to identify repeat visitors. This is statistical data about our visitors and does not personally identify any individual.

### Registration

In order to use Faithlife.com, the Faithlife Study Bible, or other Faithlife products, you will need to create an account with us. We require your name and email address. You must create a password. We do not store the password, and cannot access it or email it to you if lost; we store an encrypted hash of your password and can only email you a link to reset your password.

If you purchase something from us, we collect your address, telephone number, and credit card information as necessary to complete the transaction. We exercise great care with credit card information and follow industry-standard security procedures for storing billing information.

### Profile

You have the option of providing information about yourself as part of your Faithlife profile. You control what profile information is or is not shared on your public profile page. **However, the fact that you have an account with us may be discoverable regardless of your profile settings.** For example, a public profile page is created for every user account, identified by either a unique alias (which you may choose) or by a computer-generated user ID. By using your alias, which defaults to matching your name, by testing user IDs, or by trying to create a new alias using your name, anyone can determine if there is a Faithlife account with a certain name.

**You must be at least 13 years of age to use Faithlife.** Faithlife is neither designed nor intended for use by children under 13.

### Posting

When you post to My Faithlife or to a group, who can see your post or reply is controlled by a combination of your privacy settings and those of the group. Faithlife attempts to be clear about who can see what post, but group administrators can change the privacy settings on a group, or you could change settings on your own account, in ways that might enable users who couldn’t previously see a post to see it. When you reply to a post, or click an affirmation such as “Like” or “Praying”, it will be visible to everyone who could see the original post. All of your posts and replies are affiliated with you, and people who can see them can click through to your profile page, where you control who can see what.

### Group Membership

Faithlife is built around communities represented by Faithlife groups. The administrators of a group can customize the privacy settings for each individual group, but by default you can see posts and profiles of people who are also members of your groups. When you “Join” a group you become a member, and are in community with the other members of the group. “Followers” and “Observers” can see posts and information within a group, but are not considered “co-members” of the group and do not have co-member visibility of your My Faithlife posts and profile information.

Faithlife is built on communities, not one-to-one connections. So while you do not need to create a connection with everyone in your church in order to share with them, you also will not be notified every time someone joins or leaves your church community. New users may join a community you are a member of and gain co-member status with regards to you without your prior notification.

If you participate in communities on Faithlife, you are implicitly granting some control of your posting and profile privacy to the administrators of the groups you join; group administrators control whether a group is open or closed, and can allow new members into even closed groups.

### Geolocation

Our mobile applications ask for permission to access your location (on iPhone/iPod/iPad) or indicate their use of location in their permission profiles at download (on Android devices). If you give permission to use your location our applications will provide your location to our servers where it is used to find groups near your location, help us sort certain search results to prefer things closer to you, and to provide statistics on the use of our platform.

In the future, we plan to attach locations to posts to My Faithlife.

### Usage Information

We collect statistics on the use of our applications and web sites, including but not limited to: pages visited, features used, terms searched for, title selections, reviews, ratings, payment history, device type, unique device data, operating systems, and content accessed or rendered to screen. We use this information to find bugs, pay royalties to intellectual property owners, identify areas needing improvement in our user interface, and otherwise improve our products and offerings.

### Information Protection

We take your privacy very seriously and implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information. We use a secure server. All supplied credit card information is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and encrypted into our payment gateway provider’s database.

For your convenience, we securely store billing information for easy reuse on future transactions, but you can edit and delete billing information at any time. (Certain order transaction records may be maintained for a period of time to comply with legal and accounting regulations.)

### Cookies

We use web browser “cookies” to record information when you visit our sites. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your web browser (if you allow) that enable the sites or service providers’ systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. 

We use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart, understand and save your preferences for future visits, and compile aggregate data about site traffic and interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future. If you turn off cookies in your browser you may be unable to use certain features of our sites.

Faithlife can also gather information from IP addresses, a number assigned to all devices participating in a computer network that uses the internet protocol communication.

### Embedded Widgets

Some features of our web sites and software applications are available as ‘widgets’ that can be embedded in other sites operated by third-parties. Most of these widgets are implemented in an ‘iframe’. When you visit a third-party site with a widget from Faithlife, Biblia.com, or another Faithlife property, your web browser will load a portion of our web site within the iframe. From a technical point of view, this is just like visiting our site, only from within another site. This enables a variety of useful features: you may be able to access your Logos electronic books from a widget on another site or post a comment to My Faithlife from an article on another site. It also enables Faithlife to record the time, date, web address, and more of the site you are visiting that has embedded a Faithlife widget. 

### Affiliated Sites

We operate dozens of web sites and share accounts and information between them. Information you provide on any one of our sites may be available and used at our other sites. A list of our primary sites is online at <http://www.logos.com/websites>. 

### Information Use

We use the information we collect from you to personalize your Faithlife experience, to improve our web site and product offerings, to keep Faithlife safe and secure, to make suggestions to you about groups to join or follow, to recommend products to you, to improve customer service, to process transactions you initiate, to administer contests, promotions, surveys, and other marketing campaigns.

At times Faithlife may make certain personal information available to strategic partners. We only work with reputable partners who will respect your communication preferences.

All of our email subscriptions include clear instructions for unsubscribing. You may choose to unsubscribe from emails sent for marketing purposes or to tell you about new products.

Even if you unsubscribe, we may send you occasional one-time emails about your account. Emails are sent after you make a purchase (as receipts, and with instructions on downloading, etc.), to provide important technical/support information about our products, etc. 

Faithlife may use or disclose your personal information, when required by law, to comply with regulatory and anti-money laundering guidelines and in response to other lawful requests for information. Faithlife will not use your personal information for the purposes of targeted email marketing, phone solicitation, or invitations to participate in marketing research if you request your account be opted-out of such activity at [help@faithlife.com](mailto:help@faithlife.com) or by mail at our physical address.

### Agency

In certain transactions (particularly purchases of electronic books from some publishers) we are acting as an agent for the publisher, who is the seller in the transaction. When we act as the agent of another party in a financial transaction, the transaction is between you and the seller, and we may provide your order details to the seller.

### Aggregated Statistics

We compile aggregated statistics, stripped of personally identifiable information, about Faithlife users and share these statistics through Faithlife, internally, and with outside partners. Twenty records is the minimum number from which we compile aggregate statistics. For example, users may provide their denominational affiliation and other details on their Faithlife profile. We might tell a Faithlife group administrator that of the 350 followers of the group, 20% are Baptist, 30% are Presbyterian, and 50% are non-denominational. We might tell the author or publisher of an electronic book that 62% of the purchasers were female, or that 18% of the sales came from outside the United States. We might report that X% of My Faithlife posts were affirmed by “Praying” and Y% by “Amen” or “Like.” We might do statistical textual analysis to report that X% of My Faithlife posts that were affirmed by “Praying” contained the words “sick” or “ill” or “illness.”
